[Respect Copyright, Everyone's Responsibility]
[저작권 보호는 모두의 책임입니다]
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[천향] [십사랑 소설  각색 작품]
[Episode 33]
[제33화]
Uncle, save me!
숙부님, 살려주십시오
Let's go.
가자
Out of the way!
비켜라
Uncle.
숙부님
Miaoqing is hurt!
묘청 고모를 보십시오
The child is gone.
아이는 이미 없어졌다
Get some rest.
편히 쉬거라
Take a sip.
한 모금 마셔봐
Drink it.
약을 마셔라
I hate you.
밉습니다
I hate you!
정말 밉습니다
Immortal Lord Xuanhua,
현화 선존
why such a grand display?
이렇게 많은 사람을 이끌고 오신 이유가
What brings you here?
무엇 때문인가요?
Mr. Zuo Qiu,
좌구 선생님
I respect the academy as a pillar of the immortal sects,
저는 서원이 선문의 으뜸으로
always staying out of conflict.
다툼에 관여하지 않는 걸 압니다
But now you're harboring the Demon Lord and the Divine Tree.
하지만 이번에 마군과 건목을 숨긴
What are you trying to do?
이유가 무엇입니까?
Are you betraying the immortal sects
설마 선문을 배신하고
to side with those across the sea?
해외에 붙으려는 겁니까?
The academy has only masters and disciples.
서원에는 선생과 제자들만 있을 뿐
No Demon Lord or Divine Tree.
마군과 건목은 없습니다
A few days ago, an assassin came after me,
며칠 전 자객이 저를 암살하려다
but was rescued by the Demon Lord Yecha and the Divine Tree.
마군 야차와 건목이 구해주었지요
That assassin was struck by my fire lotus spell.
하지만 그 자객은 제 화련술에 걸려
With a little push...
조금만 힘을 주면
Look.
보십시오
The assassin, Baili Gelin, is at the academy.
자객 백리가림이 서원에 있네요
The Divine Tree and the Demon Lord are here too.
그럼 건목과 마군도 서원에 있겠지요
Ji Tongzhou,
기동주
you killed Changyue and Ye!
네가 우리 언니와 오라버니를 죽였다
As long as I draw breath,
내 숨이 붙어있는 한
I will kill you for revenge!
반드시 너를 죽여 복수할 거다
Don't move.
충동하지 마
I'll say it once more.
다신 한 번 말합니다
The academy has only masters and disciples.
수원에는 선생과 제자들만 있지
No Demon Lord, Divine Tree,
마군과 건목은 없습니다
or assassin.
자객도 없고요
Since you insist,
선생님께서 계속 부인하신다면
don't blame me for being rude.
저도 예를 갖추지 않을 수밖에 없습니다
Search.
수색하라
Yes.
예
Don't you dare!
누가 감히
Immortal Lord Xuanhua,
현화 선존
Chufeng Academy is a sacred ground of the immortal sects.
추봉서원은 선문의 경지고
They've always stayed out of disputes.
천 년 동안 분쟁에 휩쓸리지 않았습니다
You brazenly disrupt the peace of the academy.
이렇게 서원의 평온을 어지럽히시니
Aren't you afraid of public outrage?
다른 문파들의 분노가 두렵지 않습니까?
Fine.
그래요
Out of respect for the academy's teachings,
서원에서 가르침을 받은 걸 생각해서
I'll give you one day.
하루 시간을 주겠습니다
Hand over the Demon Lord and the Divine Tree by tomorrow morning.
내일 아침 마군과 건목을 내놓으십시오
Otherwise,
아니면
I'll burn Chufeng Academy to the ground
추봉서원을 불태워버려
and smoke them out.
그 두 화근을 끌어내겠습니다
I knew you two were still alive.
너희가 살아있을 거라 짐작했다
All these years, every divination I made
여태까지 매번 점을 치면
pointed to a reunion with old friends.
옛 벗과 재회하는 괘만 나왔거든
Do you two
너희 둘
have any conscience at all?
양심이 있긴 하느냐?
You're fine,
분명 살아있으면서
and you didn't even send word?
왜 사형한테 소식 한번 전하지 않았어?
Deng,
사형
you're a Sect Leader now.
이제 한 문파의 장문인데
Can you at least act like one?
품행 좀 신경 쓰십시오
You left
너 말이야
for ten whole years.
한 번 떠나니 십 년이 지났다
Do you know how worried your master was?
네 사부님께서 얼마나 걱정하셨는지 알아?
How is
사부님은
my master?
안녕하십니까?
His cultivation has dropped sharply.
네 사부님은 공력이 떨어지셔서
He's retired to Hushe Peak now.
지금은 호사봉에 은거하셨다
But he's quite carefree these days.
하지만 지금은 아주 편안하게 지내신다
He often discusses medicine and the Dao
자주 동양 사백과
with Elder Dongyang and Elder Zhu.
주옹과 함께 의술과 도를 논하신다
I almost forgot the main thing.
중요한 일을 깜빡했네
Elder Dongyang asked me
이건 동양 사백께서
to bring you this miraculous pill.
네가 전하라는 영단묘약이다
He said your cultivation has declined.
네가 지금 공력이 크게 떨어져
Take this,
이걸 복용하면
and it'll secure your future well-being.
앞으로 평생 걱정 없을 거란다
They're always so thoughtful.
역시 주옹이 세심하시군요
Xiuyuan and I could really use some medicine right now.
저랑 수원은 마침 묘약이 필요했거든요
Only one pill?
하나밖에 없나요?
What do you mean?
무슨 뜻이야?
Your master traveled far and wide,
그건 네 사부님이 수많은 산을 넘어
searching for the finest herbs,
좋은 약재를 구해
just to refine this single pill.
겨우 제련하신 거다
You've just been hurt.
방금 상처를 입었잖아
Take it.
먹어
I still have my spirit root.
나는 아직 영근이 남아 있어
I can recultivate.
다시 수련하면 돼
You...
너...
My spirit power is back?
영력이 회복되었네
The pill only strengthens the body and prolongs life.
이 영단은 몸을 튼튼하게 하고 수명을 늘려준다
Your spirit power must have returned because of the medicine.
그 영력은 네가 먹은 약의 효력일 거다
It only works once.
단 한 번만 쓸 수 있다
It doesn't matter. It's still a gain.
괜찮습니다, 한 번이라도 이득을 얻은 거니까
By the way,
맞다
Ji Tongzhou gave the academy a one-day ultimatum.
기동주가 서원에 준 하루 기한에 대해
What do you two think?
어떻게 생각하느냐?
Fight him to the death!
당연히 그와 결전을 벌여야죠
Gelin,
가림
you were imprisoned and wounded.
전에 상처를 입고
Your spirit power is weak.
영력도 미약하니
You should return to the East Sea.
먼저 동해로 돌아가십시오
No, I don't want to run away.
안 됩니다, 도망치고 싶지 않습니다
If I don't avenge Changyue and Ye,
언니와 오라버니의 원수를 갚지 않으면
I'll never have peace.
평생 마음이 편치 않을 겁니다
Even if it costs me my life,
죽는다고 한들
I'll fight him to the end.
그와 끝까지 싸우겠습니다
Ji Tongzhou has been crushing his opponents for these years.
기동주는 2년간 다른 문파를 탄압하여
He's made plenty of enemies.
모든 이의 분노를 샀다
Lately, Xingzheng Hall has wiped out several immortal sects.
요즘 성정관은 여러 선문을 멸문시키고
Wuyue Court also wants to curb his ambitions.
무월정도 그의 야망을 꺾으려 하니
This is our chance.
이번이 기회일 것이다
But what exactly is
다만 이 업화가
the karmic fire?
대체 무엇인지 모르겠다
Karmic fire comes from the inner demon.
업화는 심마에서 비롯됩니다
Mr. Zuo Qiu found the Xuanhua Sacred Fire Record
좌구 선생님께서 부도탑에서
in Futu Tower.
현화성화록을 발견하셨습니다
It says
책에 적히길
those who wield karmic fire
업화를 얻은 자는
are usually people with deep obsessions,
대부분 집념이 강해
driven to the brink of despair.
절망에 빠진 자들이랍니다
The fire
업화는
is their only weapon of retaliation.
그들이 가진 유일한 반격의 무기고
That's why it's also called the fire of the inner demon.
예전에는 심마의 화라고 불렸습니다
Inner demon?
심마...
Is this the aftermath of the mirage dream
설마 방호도의 신몽이
on Fanghu Island?
심은 화근이 아닐까?
Karmic fire is born from the inner demon.
업화는 심마에 비롯된 것이니
So if we get rid of the inner demon,
심마를 잘라버리면
the fire will die out?
업화도 사라질 것이다
Not that easy.
말처럼 쉽지 않다
To get rid of the inner demon,
심마를 잘라버리려면
you must first understand the obsession.
심결부터 알아야 한다
I know what his obsession is.
제가 그의 심결을 알고 있습니다
But even knowing it,
심결을 안다고 해도
we'd have to push him to the edge before we could act.
그를 궁지로 몰아넣어야 쓸 수 있다
And who in this world
하지만 이 세상에
can push Immortal Lord Xuanhua to the edge?
누가 현화 선존을 상대할 수 있겠나?
Let me try.
제가 해보겠습니다
Mr. Zuo already knew you'd say that.
선생님께서는 네 결정을 예상하셨다
Follow me.
따라와라
Human strength has its limits.
인간의 힘엔 한계가 있습니다
In just one day,
짧은 며칠 만에
how can Xiuyuan stand against Immortal Lord Xuanhua?
수원이 어떻게 현화 선존과 상대할 수 있습니까?
One person's strength is limited.
한 사람의 힘은 한계가 있지만
But when generations share the same will,
수십 대의 사람들의 마음과
spanning centuries without end,
백 년 천 년 끊이지 않은 소원은
it becomes limitless.
무궁무진하다
Sir.
선생님
You only have one chance.
너에게는 단 한 번의 기회밖에 없다
Hold Ji Tongzhou back.
기동주를 붙잡아
Help Lifei turn the tide!
려비가 위기를 이겨내도록 도와라
Mr. Zuo, you gave him the academy's spirit energy.
선생님, 서원의 영기를 그에게 주셨어요?
Thousands of years ago,
천 년 전
I founded Chufeng Academy.
내가 추봉서원을 세운 건
It was meant to be a place beyond the affairs of this world.
속세를 벗어난 초월한 공간을 남기기 위함이었다
Yet all things in this world are connected.
하지만 세상 만물은 서로 얽혀 있으니
Nothing is truly detached.
어찌 초월이 가능하겠나?
My spirit root was destroyed long ago.
아쉽게도 나의 영근은 오래전 훼손되어
I've only survived on the academy's spirit energy.
서원의 영기에 의지해 살아왔을 뿐이다
Now
지금은
it's up to the younger generation.
이 후배에게 기대를 맡기겠다
Mr. Zuo, you sacrificed your cultivation
선생님께서 그해 산해결계를 만들기 위해
to build the mountain-sea barrier,
자기 수위를 희생하셔서
protecting the Central Plains
중토의 평안을 지키셨고
and preserving the flame of the immortal sects.
선문을 위해 불씨를 남겨주셨습니다
From now on, it's these flames that will carry on.
이제는 이 불씨들의 세상이다
Mr...
선...
Mr. Zuo.
선생님
With growth comes decay.
흥하면 쇠약해지기도 마련이다
Let nature take its course.
흐름에 맡겨라
Don't dwell on it.
집착할 필요 없다
We don't know if we'll survive tomorrow's battle.
내일의 싸움은 생사를 알 수 없습니다
I'm dragging you into this again.
또 폐를 끼치게 됐네요, 사형
Silly.
바보야
We're husband and wife.
부부는 한 마음이니
We live and die together.
본래 생사를 함께해야 한다
I want to stay at the academy.
저는 서원에 남고 싶어요
Why?
왜?
When I was young, I relied on Changyue and Ye.
어릴 적, 언니와 오라버니한테 의지했고
In the East Sea,
동해에 와서
I had Jiao and you.
사저와 사형이 있었고
I always hesitated before doing anything.
뭐든 앞뒤를 재고 망설이고
My cultivation was average.
수위도 평범했고
I never knew
자신이 뭘 원하는지
what I truly wanted.
모르고 있었습니다
But today,
하지만 오늘
watching the masters
선생님들이
stand up to Ji Tongzhou,
기동주와 맞서는 모습을 보고
I finally understood.
갑자기 깨달았습니다
Even dust may fight the storm.
개미가 나무를 흔들어도 소용이 없겠지만
We ordinary people have our own reason for being.
저처럼 평범한 사람들에게도 살아가는 의미가 있습니다
So I want to stay.
그래서 남아서
I want to show my future juniors
사제 사매들에게 가르치고 싶습니다
what it means that all beings are equal,
평등이 무엇이고
to fear no power,
권세를 두려워하지 않는 것이 무엇이고
to hold a sense of justice,
협의의 마음이 무엇이고
and to walk the Great Dao.
천지 대도가 무엇인지
Alright.
그래
Then we'll
그럼 우리 함께
seek the Great Dao together.
천지 대도를 찾아가자
You're finally here.
드디어 왔구나
Come at me together.
함께 덤벼라
Save me the trouble.
여러 번 손대지 않아도 되게 말이다
Form the formation!
진을 펼쳐라
Demon-Subduing Formation?
건곤복마진
You dare use that against me?
감히 이 진을 펼쳐 날 상대하려 하다니
Ridiculous.
웃기는군
Fire and metal unite. The karmic fire is merciless.
금화동귀 업화무정
Your own karmic fire.
네 업화를
Take it back!
돌려주마
This is the academy's spirit energy?
이건 서원의 영기다
You are the Demon Lord.
너는 마군인데
Why are they helping you?
저들은 왜 너를 돕는 거냐?
Spirit power knows no divide.
영력에는 선악이 없고
Good and evil dwell in the heart!
선악은 오직 마음에 달렸다
Tongzhou,
동주
you're at your end.
너는 이미 궁지에 몰렸다
Time to turn back.
제발 손을 거두어라
Tongzhou.
사촌 오라버니
Tongzhou, why are you asleep?
사촌 오라버니, 왜 잠들었습니까?
Lanya?
란아
What... what are you doing here?
네가 왜 여기 있느냐?
What's wrong, Tongzhou?
왜 그래요?
Do you hate me?
란아가 싫어서
Not happy to see me?
란아를 만나기 싫습니까?
I.. I am happy.
아니다
Tongzhou,
동주
what's wrong?
왜 그러시오?
Did you not sleep well last night?
어젯밤에 못 잤소?
Ye Ye?
엽엽
Ye Ye, you're alive?
엽엽, 아직 살아있었소?
What are you talking about?
아니, 무슨 소리요?
Your Highness,
왕야
you're still half asleep?
아직 잠이 덜 깼나 봐요
Tongzhou, Mr. Hu is here.
오라버니, 호 선생님께서 오셨어요
Sit down.
얼른 앉아요
Class is about to start.
곧 수업 시작이다
Do you all
너희들
want to be punished?
벌을 받고 싶냐?
Ji Tongzhou!
기동주
Dazing off?
멍하니 뭘 보고 있어?
Still sleepy?
잠이 덜 깼나?
Were you dreaming?
꿈이라도 꿨어?
A dream?
꿈...
Just a dream.
꿈이었다
It really was just a dream.
역시 꿈이었어
Lifei.
려비
Xiuyuan!
수원
Lifei! Xiuyuan!
려비, 수원
Lifei.
려비
I just had the longest dream.
나 방금 아주 긴 꿈을 꿨다
What did you dream about?
무슨 꿈을 꾸셨습니까?
I dreamed...
꿈에서...
Forget it. Don't tell dreams in broad daylight.
됐다, 대낮에 꿈 이야기는 그만하자
My brother brought lots of food.
황형께서 맛있는 걸 많이 가져왔단다
Everyone will love it.
다들 좋아할 거다
Xiuyuan, join us.
수원, 같이 먹지
Let's go.
가자
Need to knead it more.
좀 더 주물러야 해
- Changyue. - Like this.
언니, 이렇게
I got it, Changyue.
나 할 줄 알아
You're doing so well.
잘 만들었네
Almost done. See?
거의 다 됐네
Tongzhou,
동주
come make mooncakes with us.
같이 월병 만들어요
Done.
그래
Drink till we drop!
취할 때까지 마십시오
Drink till we drop.
취할 때까지 마십시다
Here.
자
Come on.
자, 어서
Let's release this wish lantern together.
함께 소원등을 띄우죠
Sure.
좋소
But what should we write?
하지만 뭐라고 쓸까?
"May we be together forever."
오래도록 함께하길
"The same every year."
해마다 오늘 같은 날이 오길
Alright.
좋아요
[May we be together forever. The same every year.]
[오래도록 함께하길 해마다 오늘 같은 날이 오길]
If only time could stop right here.
이 순간이 영원히 멈췄으면 좋겠네
Right, Tongzhou?
그렇죠, 동주?
Don't go!
가지 마
Immortal Lord Xuanhua?
현화 선존
That...
이게...
That's me?
나다
Tongzhou.
동주
Time to wake up.
이제 깰 때가 됐소
Tongzhou, we never blamed you.
동주, 우린 그대를 탓하지 않소
Sorry.
미안하다
I'm sorry.
정말 미안하다
Why don't you blame me?
왜 날 탓하지 않는 것이냐?
I did so many wrong things.
내가 그렇게 많은 잘못을 저질렀는데
A dream. Just a dream.
꿈이다, 다 꿈이었다
All of this was a dream!
모든 건 꿈이었다
What's happening?
어떻게 된 거지?
His mind is broken.
그는 심경이 무너져
He can't use Xuanhua Fire anymore.
현화지화를 쓸 수 없습니다
Ji Tongzhou, pay with your life!
기동주, 목숨으로 갚아라
No.
안 돼
Miaoqing.
묘청
♪The warmth within my arms♪
♪품 안에 가득했던 그대의 온기♪
♪I can no longer hold on to♪
♪내 이제는 끝내 붙잡지 못하네♪
♪In the cold night, how can I♪
♪시린 이 겨울밤, 그대를 어떻게 다시♪
♪Keep you warm until sunrise?♪
♪동이 틀 때까지 따스하게 품어줄까♪
Miaoqing.
묘청
♪My heartbeat freezes♪
♪가슴은 차갑게 얼어붙고♪
Your Highness.
왕야
Does it hurt?
아픕니까?
♪I can no longer tell you♪
♪마음을 전할 길조차 없는데♪
♪Looking you in the eyes, I cannot♪
♪그대 눈을 보며 하려던 그 한마디♪
♪Utter that line♪
♪끝내 입 밖으로 내지 못하네♪
♪Knowing love and hate♪
♪애증과 아픔, 깊어진 상처가 밀려와♪
♪Pain and wounds cannot be stopped♪
♪차마 막을 수 없음을 알면서도♪
Your Highness.
왕야
♪I still linger on♪
♪난 여전히 그대를 그리워하며♪
♪Unwilling to let go of every inch of our past♪
♪겹겹이 쌓인 지난날을 놓지 못하네♪
No.
안 아프다
Doesn't hurt.
괜찮아질 거다
♪Last night's stars cast faint glimmers♪
♪어젯밤 하늘을 수놓던 아스라한 별빛♪
♪But we thought nothing of it♪
♪그때는 어찌 당연하게 여겼을까♪
I came to tell you
저는 왕야가 밉다고
that when I said I hated you,
얘기한 게 다 거짓이라고
I was lying.
알리러 왔습니다
Don't cry.
울지 마십시오
I love you.
묘청은 왕야를 마음에 품고 있습니다
♪Running relentlessly without regret♪
♪미련 없이 거칠게 발버둥 치는구나♪
Until death.
죽을 때까지 변치 않습니다
♪The storm looms, yet the wind stands in its way♪
♪몰아치는 비바람 온몸으로 막아서며♪
♪A final farewell left on the cliff♪
♪절벽 끝자락에 눈물로 새긴 서약♪
Miaoqing.
묘청
♪Leaping straight into that heartbreaking past♪
♪내 기꺼이 이 몸을 던지리라 살을 도려내는 듯한 아픈 기억 속으로♪
Miaoqing, wake up!
묘청, 일어나봐
Miaoqing.
묘청
♪My breath is about to stop♪
♪내 숨결이 점차 희미해지고♪
♪Those hands can no longer hold yours♪
♪맞잡은 그 손을 더는 쥘 수 없으니♪
♪Through the future snow, wind, and fog♪
♪앞으로 다가올 시린 바람과 안개를♪
♪Who will be there by your side?♪
♪이제 누구와 함께 견뎌내야 할까♪
♪I smile as it ends♪
♪미소를 지으며 눈을 감는 것은♪
♪Afraid that you might cry for me♪
♪나로 인해 그대 슬피 울까 염려되어♪
♪Quietly, I turn into a sky lantern♪
♪말없이 공명등 한 줄기 빛이 되어♪
Let him go.
그를 놓아줘요
He's probably
지금
♪To light your way through the night♪
♪그대가 걷는 어두운 밤길을 비추어 주리♪
in more pain than death right now.
죽는 것보다 더 고통스러울 테니
♪Knowing love and hate♪
♪애증과 아픔, 깊어진 상처가 밀려와♪
♪Pain and wounds cannot be stopped♪
♪차마 막을 수 없음을 알면서도♪
♪I still linger on♪
♪난 여전히 그대를 그리워하며♪
♪Unwilling to let go of every inch of our past♪
♪겹겹이 쌓인 지난날을 놓지 못하네♪
♪Last night's stars cast faint glimmers♪
♪어젯밤 하늘을 수놓던 아스라한 별빛♪
♪But we thought nothing of it♪
♪그때는 어찌 당연하게 여겼을까♪
♪With a heartbroken cry♪
♪가슴이 찢어지는 듯한 애달픈 외침으로♪
♪I wish you well♪
♪오직 그대의 안녕만을 바라네♪
♪Knowing right and wrong♪
♪옳고 그름도, 흑백의 경계도♪
♪Black and gray are all illusions♪
♪검고 흐린 세상사 모두 부질없거늘♪
♪You're still screaming♪
♪그대는 여전히 목 놓아 울부짖으며♪
♪Running relentlessly without regret♪
♪미련 없이 거칠게 발버둥 치는구나♪
♪The storm looms, yet the wind stands in its way♪
♪몰아치는 비바람 온몸으로 막아서며♪
♪A final farewell left on the cliff♪
♪절벽 끝자락에 눈물로 새긴 서약♪
♪I'd shatter my soul♪
♪살을 도려내는 듯한 아픔으로♪
♪To lay all your days in peace♪
♪남은 그대의 인생이 부디 평탄하기를♪
♪Who says that love and hate♪
♪애증과 아픔, 깊어진 상처가 밀려와♪
♪Pain and wounds cannot be stopped?♪
♪차마 막을 수 없음을 누가 알랴♪
♪I will level the seas and mountains♪
♪내 저 산과 바다를 평정하고♪
♪Break the waves, no matter how mad it seems♪
♪풍랑이 미쳐 날뛴대도 두렵지가 않네♪
♪The storm looms, yet I stand in its way♪
♪닥쳐오는 비바람을 내 기어이 가로막으리♪
♪Torn inside, still I burn bright♪
♪가슴이 무너져 내릴지라도 참으로 감미롭구나♪
♪With the light from my fingertips, I build a paradise♪
♪내 손끝에 맺힌 마지막 빛으로 그대와 함께할 낙원을 세워♪
♪To wander with you♪
♪영원히 그대 곁을 거닐고 싶어라♪
What are you doing?
뭘 하는 겁니까?
No take-backs.
바둑을 두었으면 후회는 없다
Know what "no take-backs" means?
후회는 없다니요?
Do you even know how to play?
바둑을 둘 줄은 알아요?
Move your hand.
손 치워요
I put it here,
제가 여기에 대고
but I haven't let go yet.
손을 치우지도 않았는데
Does that count as a move?
바둑을 두었다고 할 수 있나요?
I'm still holding it.
아직 손에 쥐고 있는데
Does that count?
바둑을 두었다니요
It's called thinking.
고민하고 있었잖아요
You just put it right there.
방금 여기에 두었잖아
It's called thinking. Understand?
고민이라고
Do you know how to play?
바둑을 둘 줄 알기나 하나
If you don't,
둘 줄 모르면
let's just stop.
그만해요
Don't be a sore loser.
꾀부리지 마라
Sore loser?
꾀라니요
You just put it there.
너 방금 여기에 두었잖아
Hey! Give that back!
이리 줘요
How dare you steal my wine?
왜 내 술을 훔쳐요?
Why are you getting stingier with age?
왜 나이 먹을수록 이렇게 인색해요?
Stingy?
인색이라니요
This is the wine Lifei and Xiuyuan gave me.
이건 려비와 수원이 준 거요
If you want wine, drink your own.
마실 거면 자기 거 마셔요
Didn't they give you some too?
당신한테 줬잖소
I finished mine last night.
내 술은 어젯밤에 다 마셨다고
What's that got to do with me?
그게 나랑 무슨 상관이오?
Just let me have one sip.
한 모금만
Go away.
저리 비키시오
Just one sip.
한 모금만 마시게 해다오
Hey.
그게 아니라
Just one sip. One sip.
딱 한 모금만 마시겠다고
What are you doing?
왜 이러는 거요?
Getting all worked up?
화를 내네?
I'm telling you,
알려주는데
if you keep this up,
계속 이러면
I'll report you to Mr. Deng.
등 장문한테 가서 고발할 거요
I'll report you for being shameless,
나이 먹고 품행이 바르지 않고
a drunkard,
술에 미쳤고
and disgracing Wuyue Court!
우리 무월정 선문의 체면을 구겼다고
You old geezer.
늙다리 같으니
I...
아니
You'll report me? I'll report you!
날 고발한다고? 내가 당신을 고발하겠소
For having bad chess etiquette!
바둑을 꾀로 둔다고 고발할 거요
Alright.
됐소
For going back on your word!
말을 번복하고
Xiguang is busy.
계광은 엄청 바쁠 것인데
He doesn't have time for this.
이런 사소한 일 신경 쓸 틈이 없소
It's just wine.
고작 술이잖아
Have mine.
내 걸 마셔요
This is from Lifei and Xiuyuan.
려비와 수원이 준 거요
That's more like it.
이래야지
Look at him.
좀 배우시오
Here.
자
Cheers.
같이 마시자고
Look at you two.
두 사람이 정말로
Can you act like elders?
어른답지가 않구려
Leave some for me.
나에게 한 모금은 남기시오
Fame and glory all over the capital.
꽃이 온 경성에 피었거늘
♪I trade all the mortal world's splendor♪
♪내 인간 세상의 부귀영화를 쥐고♪
♪For a fleeting moment with you♪
♪그대와 함께할 찰나의 순간과 바꾸리♪
Just a dream in the end.
꿈과 다름이 없지
♪Our fates intertwined, embracing yet fighting♪
♪얽히고설킨 숙명 속에 서로를 품고 스러지니♪
♪The hardest bond to balance♪
♪이 인연을 맺기가 가장 어렵구나♪
All empty.
텅텅 비어 있으니
♪Obsessed and struggling, a thousand thoughts arise♪
♪집착 속에 아파하며 온갖 마음을 내어 보아도♪
♪Love sprouts again in this lifetime♪
♪이번 생의 애달픈 사랑은 다시 움트네♪
♪No calamity can rival♪
♪수많은 겁난도♪
♪The lingering thread of a fragrance♪
♪향기로운 미련을 이기지 못해♪
♪With you, through mountains falling and seas turning to sand♪
♪산이 무너지고 바다가 모래가 될 때까지 그대와 함께하리♪
♪Withered branches burst into bloom♪
♪말라버린 나뭇가지에 다시 꽃이 피어나듯♪
♪Hand in hand on the Naihe Bridge. Past the pagoda♪
♪굳게 손잡고 나하교를 건너 부도탑을 지나♪
♪in fine robes on galloping horses♪
♪비단옷 걸치고 거침없이 달리리라♪
Miaoqing.
묘청
♪Always, at the very end of obsession♪
♪언제나 모진 집착의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of softness♪
♪내 마음이 스르르 무너지던 그 순간♪
♪Betrayed by all, I still♪
♪세상에 버림받고 모두가 등 돌린들♪
♪Reign supreme♪
♪어떠하리♪
♪With you, we melt into mist and haze♪
♪기꺼이 그대와 함께 환영으로 화하리라♪
Three-one-zero.
삼일공
- This is your exam number. - Three-one-zero.
- 여기 번호 받고 - 삼일공
Go line up over there.
저쪽으로 가서 줄 서라
Three-one-zero.
삼일공
What's your name?
넌 이름이 뭐냐?
Three-two-two.
삼일이
This is my clan nephew, Xing.
여긴 제 종조카, 소성입니다
You can tell he's a fine young monster.
딱 봐도 요족의 인재로군
Come on.
자
This is your exam number.
이건 네 번호다
Good luck!
힘내
Three-two-nine.
삼이구
What's your name?
너는 이름이 뭐냐?
Which clan?
어느 종족이냐?
Three-two-nine.
삼이구
This is your exam number.
여기 번호
Here.
이거요
Okay.
그래
Go line up over there.
저쪽으로 가서 줄 서라
Today is everyone's first day at the academy.
오늘 다들 서원 첫날이니
First, you must know that the path of cultivation
수련하는 데 가장 중요한 걸 알아야 한다
requires a dedicated heart.
바로 수련하는 마음이다
What is a dedicated heart?
수련하는 마음이 무엇인가
It could be for a personal wish
자신의 소원일 수도 있고
or for the greater good.
이 세상의 모든 생명을 위함일 수도 있다
Turn to the first page.
오늘 먼저 첫 장을 보도록 하자
No wonder the Lord wanted to stay in the Central Plains.
존상께서 중토에 남으셔서 돌아오지 않는 이유가 있으셨네요
The people and the food here are wonderful.
여기 사람들도 음식도 정말 좋네요
You folks from across the sea are wonderful too.
해외 종족들도 좋잖아요
So carefree.
자유롭고 편안하고
What's it like across the sea?
해외는 어떤 모습입니까?
We have thousands of islands.
저희는 천주만도가 있습니다
Each one is different.
섬마다 풍경이 다릅니다
There are mermaids in the sea
바다에 사는 교인도 있고
and winged unicorns.
날개 달린 독각수도 있습니다
There are winged unicorns?
날개 달린 독각수라고요?
Of course.
그럼요
They must be able to fly.
그럼 날 수 있겠네요
Don't believe me?
안 믿으면
I'll take you to see them someday.
나중에 데리고 가서 구경시켜 줄게요
Good!
그래요
I wonder how Lifei is doing.
려비는 어떻게 지낼까요?
Probably like us.
아마도 우리와 마찬가지로
Wherever she goes, he follows.
부부끼리 따라다니겠지
[The Demon Lord's Beloved Wife. The Immortal Lord's Undying Love]
[마군의 아내, 선존의 목숨을 건 사랑]
Turn in your manuscript now.
어서 원고 넘겨라
The Central Plains and those across the sea love your work.
중토와 해외에서 반응이 뜨겁다
Especially the Chufeng Trilogy.
특히 추봉 삼부작이
It's sparked a wave of new applicants to the academy.
서원 입시 열풍을 몇 차례나 일으켰다
You must turn in the next chapters
내일 진시 내로
by Chen hour tomorrow.
새로은 장을 반드시 제출하라
Or else...
아니면...
Always rushing!
재촉하지 말라고
Annoying book merchants.
악독한 상인 놈
Lifei, food's ready!
려비, 밥 먹자
Dear, your cooking keeps getting better.
서방 요리 솜씨가 갈수록 좋아지네
Here.
자
Have a piece of meat.
상으로 고기 한 점 줄게
Dear, your storybooks are a hit.
낭자의 화본이 잘 팔려
The bookshop's profits just got us another ten mu of land.
서국에서 받은 돈 덕에 밭 열 묘가 더 생겼다
Here.
자
Have some radish.
무 한 점 상으로 줄게
Delicious.
맛있네
Have some greens.
채소 한 입 더 먹어
Here.
자
Are you two treating me like air?
나는 여우지, 강아지가 아니다
Alright.
그래
Then let's feed him together.
그럼 같이 먹여주자
You, eat.
네가 먹어
Come on.
자
Here.
먹어
Try some.
한 입 먹어봐
- Stop running! - Just one bite.
- 왜 도망가 - 한 입만
One bite and you'll know. It's amazing.
한 입만 먹으면 안다니까, 엄청 맛있어
Try some radish.
이 무 먹어봐
Why are you running so fast?
왜 그렇게 빨리 도망가?
I grew it myself!
내가 심은 거라고
Stop him, Lifei!
잡아, 려비
Amazing radish!
이 무가 맛있다고
[The Eternal Fragrance]
[천향] [십사랑 소설  각색 작품]
♪I trade all the mortal world's splendor♪
♪내 인간 세상의 부귀영화를 쥐고♪
♪For a fleeting moment with you♪
♪그대와 함께할 찰나의 순간과 바꾸리♪
♪Our fates intertwined, embracing yet fighting♪
♪얽히고설킨 숙명 속에 서로를 품고 스러지니♪
♪The hardest bond to balance♪
♪이 인연을 맺기가 가장 어렵구나♪
♪Obsessed and struggling, a thousand thoughts arise♪
♪집착 속에 아파하며 온갖 마음을 내어 보아도♪
♪Love sprouts again in this lifetime♪
♪이번 생의 애달픈 사랑은 다시 움트네♪
♪No calamity can rival the lingering thread of a fragrance♪
♪수많은 겁난도 향기로운 미련을 이기지 못해♪
♪With you, through mountains falling and seas turning to sand♪
♪산이 무너지고 바다가 모래가 될 때까지 그대와 함께하리♪
♪Withered branches burst into bloom♪
♪말라버린 나뭇가지에 다시 꽃이 피어나듯♪
♪Hand in hand on the Naihe Bridge♪
♪굳게 손잡고 나하교를 건너♪
♪Past the pagoda, in fine robes on galloping horses♪
♪부도탑을 지나 비단옷 걸치고 거침없이 달리리라♪
♪Always, at the very end of obsession♪
♪언제나 모진 집착의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of softness♪
♪내 마음이 스르르 무너지던 그 순간♪
♪Betrayed by all, I still reign supreme♪
♪세상에 버림받고 모두가 등 돌린들 어떠하리♪
♪With you, we melt into mist and haze♪
♪기꺼이 그대와 함께 환영으로 화하리라♪
♪I trade the highest heaven and endless clouds♪
♪내 구만장천의 붉은 노을을 딛고♪
♪For a fleeting moment with you♪
♪그대와 함께할 찰나의 순간과 바꾸리♪
♪Pierced by countless arrows, pain and illness pile on♪
♪만 개의 화살이 심장을 꿰뚫는 고통이 밀려와도♪
♪Yet I remain silent♪
♪그저 묵묵히 소리 없이 삼키네♪
♪Deep love and long yearning, a kiss falls into a dream♪
♪깊어 가는 정과 그리움은 꿈결 속에 내려앉고♪
♪In the distant night, bitterness blooms♪
♪외롭고 긴 밤하늘 아래 쓰라린 꽃이 피어나네♪
♪The grand chapter is rewritten, startling the whole world♪
♪찬란한 운명을 다시 쓰니 온 세상이 경탄하누나♪
♪With you, through mountains falling and seas turning to sand♪
♪산이 무너지고 바다가 모래가 될 때까지 그대와 함께하리♪
♪Withered branches burst into bloom♪
♪말라버린 나뭇가지에 다시 꽃이 피어나듯♪
♪Hand in hand on the Naihe Bridge♪
♪굳게 손잡고 나하교를 건너♪
♪Past the pagoda, in fine robes on galloping horses♪
♪부도탑을 지나 비단옷 걸치고 거침없이 달리리라♪
♪Always, at the very end of obsession♪
♪언제나 모진 집착의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of softness♪
♪내 마음이 스르르 무너지던 그 순간♪
♪Betrayed by all, I still reign supreme♪
♪세상에 버림받고 모두가 등 돌린들 어떠하리♪
♪If the seal can't be broken, then let it go♪
♪얽매인 봉인을 풀 수 없다면 차라리 내려놓으리♪
♪Where the heart finds peace, there is home♪
♪내 마음 편히 쉴 곳이 곧 나의 집이어라♪
♪Side by side, we fly through seas of clouds♪
♪비익조가 되어 구름바다를 가로지르고♪
♪Break through the waves; the heart's ocean knows no shore♪
♪거친 파도를 깨부수니 마음의 바다는 끝이 없어라♪
♪Always, at the very end of fate♪
♪언제나 가혹한 숙명의 그 끝자락에서♪
♪Comes that one moment of defiance♪
♪끝까지 모질게 버텨내던 그 순간♪
♪In the human world or above, like flowing water and falling petals♪
♪천상과 인간 세상사 모두 흐르는 물과 지는 꽃 같으니♪
♪Let this fleeting life be whatever it may♪
♪덧없는 이 허무한 삶을 그저 순리에 맡기리라♪